Hi, I'm Jan Kain and I'm back again to tell you a little about Chi Gong.
Now we're going to go into the breathing and grounding.
Very, very important before we actually even get started.
There's probably the most important thing that you're going to be able to do, if you're in standing position, you're going to be in the neutral standing position with the feet about as wide as your hips, tail bone tucked under, and nice and strong.
Spine is straight, chin's tucked, and you're looking straight ahead.
Arms are right down by your sides, relaxed but strong.
So just imagine that you have roots coming out of your feet going right into the earth.
It's really, really important to feel centered and feel grounded and feel at one with the earth.
If you're in seated position, you can still be grounded, you can do the same thing, but just imagine that you're grounding not only through your feet, but up through your tail bone and right into your lower spine.
One of the most important things about Chi Gong is to realize the elements of the earth and of nature, along with all the elements of your body and all the systems.
Now that we're grounded in standing position, we're going to talk a little bit about breathing.
The breathing is in through the nose and out through the nose and mouth.
So let's try just a couple of these.
Inhale and exhale.
And, again, inhale and exhale.
Just imagine your lungs are like two big balloons, you want to make sure that they fill completely and empty completely.
You will automatically feel a great sense of calm if you breathe in this fashion.
So now that we know about the grounding and the breath, let's move on.